Register of the Roderick Scott papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Roderick Scott papers
1916-1967
72002
Hoover Institution Archives
3 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize folder (1.6 linear feet)
The papers include correspondence, reports, newsletters, writings, photographs, and memorabilia from both Scott and his wife, Agnes Kelley Scott, relating to missionary activity and Christian education in China. Also includes materials generated by and about Fukien Christian University (FCU), where Scott spent almost thirty years of his life.
Scott, Roderick, 1885-
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1972.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Related Materials
Roderick Scott (Series 15), American Missionaries and Educators in China Collection, Special Collections, Honnold Mudd Library, Claremont University Consortium, Claremont, CA
Biographical Note
1885 Born, Auburn, New York
1902 Graduated from Haverford School, Haverford, Pennsylvania
1906 Bachelor of Arts, Haverford College
1907 Master of Arts, Haverford College
1908 Master of Arts, Harvard University
1908-1909 Instructor in English, Bowdoin College
1909-1913 Assistant professor of English, Earlham College
1913-1914 Secretary in the Foreign Student YMCA, Petrograd, Russia
1914-1915 Secretary of the city YMCA, Vincennes, Indiana
1915-1916 Assistant professor in English, Oberlin College
1916 Appointed by the American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions to build a new Christian college in Fuzhou, China
1916-1923 Professor of English, Fukien Christian University (FCU), Fuzhou, China
1919-1920, 1921-1925 Acting president, FCU
1920-1930 Dean, FCU
1922-1923 Graduate student, Columbia University
1922-1923, 1930-1931 Graduate student, Union Theological Seminary
1925-1940 Professor of philosophy, FCU
1930 Author, The Seeker Finds
1933 Author, A Logic for Living
1940 Honorary Doctor of Divinity, Pacific School of Religion
1940-1949 Professor of western culture, FCU
1946 Doctor of Philosophy in Chinese philosophy, University of Southern California
1947-1949 Associate dean, FCU
Circa 1950-1957 Professor of philosophy, Olivet College, Michigan
1954 Author, Fukien Christian University
1971 Died, Claremont, California
Scope and Content of Collection
The papers include correspondence, reports, newsletters, writings, photographs, and memorabilia from both Scott and his wife, Agnes Kelley Scott relating to missionary activity and Christian education in China. Also includes materials generated by and about Fukien Christian University (FCU), where Scott spent almost thirty years of his life.
The papers as a whole offer a perspective on the social conditions in China during very turbulent times, including World War II and the Chinese civil war in 1949. "[The papers] document the rise of anti-foreigner sentiment in the 1920s, the debates over the Sinicization of western institutions in the years that followed, the solidarity displayed by foreign missionaries toward the Chinese" at such a volatile time.
Source:
Bauer, Brad. "Wading into the stream of Chinese life: the life and missionary career of Roderick Scott in China, 1916-1949." Journal of Modern Chinese History, 3:1, 71-88.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into 6 series: Correspondence, Fukien Christian University (FCU) file, Speeches and writings, Subject file, Photographs, and Memorabilia
American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions.; Fukien Christian University.; Education--China.; Missionaries.; Missions--China.; Universities and colleges--China.
- Correspondence, 1916-1967
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes letters to and from Roderick Scott and his wife Agnes Kelley Scott, as well as newsletters and reports they created. Arranged by format
  - Newsletters and reports, 1927-1952 (Box-folder 1: 1-2)
  - Letters and postcards, 1916, 1926-1967 (Box-folder 1: 3-6)
- Fukien Christian University (FCU) file, 1920s-1956
  Consists of documents regarding FCU alumni, correspondence, newsletters, published materials and reports. Arranged according to document type. See also Speeches and Writings, Photographs, and Memorabilia
  - Alumni lists and related documents, circa 1926-1952 (Box-folder 1: 7)
  - Correspondence, 1928-1949 (Box-folder 1: 8)
    Includes correspondence not directly to or from Roderick Scott
  - F.C.U. News, 1930, 1934, 1937 (Box-folder 1: 9)
  - Newsletters, 1951-1956 (Box-folder 1: 10)
  - Published booklets and pamphlets, 1920s-1941 (Box-folder 1: 11)
  - Reports, 1926-1933 (Box-folder 1: 12)
  - Miscellany, undated (Box-folder 1: 13)
- Speeches and writings, 1931-1965, undated
  Comprised of Roderick Scott's essays, presentations, and other forms of writing, as well as his doctoral thesis from the University of Southern California. Arranged chronologically.
  - "Detailed Account of the Affair of the Revolt of the 'Sek-Siong Party,'", 1927 March (Box-folder 2: 1)
  - "Narrative of part of journey of A. & R. Scott,", 1931 December-1932 January (Box-folder 2: 2)
  - Sermons translated into Chinese, 1932-1940s, undated (Box-folder 2: 3)
  - "Not My Country and Not My People" from The Chinese Recorder, 1936 December (Box-folder 2: 4)
  - "Advance Through Storm: Address to the Prudential Committee of the American Board,", 1945 April 10 (Box-folder 2: 5)
  - "The Personalistic Insights in Ancient Chinese Philosophy,", circa 1946 (Box-folder 2: 6)
  - The Personalistic Insights in Ancient Chinese Philosophy, dissertation for the University of Southern California, 1946 June (Box-folder 2: 7-9)
  - "An ... Student 'Movement' in China,", 1947-1948 (Box-folder 2: 10)
  - "Sermon on Hope,", 1948 May 2 (Box-folder 2: 11)
  - "Christianity for this Day in China" seminar notes, 1949 September 17 (Box-folder 2: 12)
    Scott made a presentation
  - The United Nations and the Missionary Movement, 1950 April (Box-folder 2: 13)
  - Fukien Christian University, paperbound book, 1954 (Box-folder 2: 14)
  - "Memories of Doctor C.M.L. Sites,", 1960 September (Box-folder 2: 15)
  - What I Have Learned, or My New Theology, circa 1965 (Box-folder 2: 16)
  - "Little Essays on the Chinese Classics,", undated (Box-folder 2: 17)
  - "On Understanding China: What About China?", undated (Box-folder 2: 18)
  - "Tehism and Christianity,", undated (Box-folder 2: 19)
- Subject file, 1926-1962
  Consists of articles, reports, memoranda, and other materials collected by Scott. The bulk of the materials relate to Christian education and missionary work in China. Arranged alphabetically by title or topic.
  - American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions bulletins and memorandum, 1941-1943, 1950 (Box-folder 2: 20)
  - The Chinese Recorder, 1926-1933 (Box-folder 2: 21)
    Bound copy consisting of excerpts from the publication
  - Christians and Christian education in China file, 1939-1962 (Box-folder 3: 1)
  - "Former Richmond Resident Describes Chinese Events" article from The Richmond Sun-Telegram featuring Agnes Scott, 1927 August 22 (Box-folder 3: 2)
  - "The Moral Point of View of Chang Tsai" by Siu-chi Huang, 1971 April (Box-folder 3: 3)
    Reprinted from Philosophy East & West, Volume 21, number 2. Huang graduated from FCU in 1936
  - New Educational Buildings in War-Torn China by Ching-jun Lin, 1938 October 15 (Box-folder 3: 4)
    Translation of an address given at the dedication of the Orlinda Childs Pierce Memorial School
  - The Perfections of God According to Doctor Karl Barth, thesis by Peter (Ping K'ang) Hsieh, for FCU, 1943 (Box-folder 3: 5)
  - Religious Education Fellowships excerpts, 1947, 1948 (Box-folder 3: 6)
  - "Science, Scientists and Politics" by Theodore Hsi-en Chen, 1961 (Box-folder 3: 7)
    Reprinted from Sciences in Communist China American Association for the Advancement of Science. Chen graduated from FCU in 1922
  - Miscellany, 1947, 1972 (Box-folder 3: 8)
- Photographs, 1927-circa 1933
  Consists of group photographs of the faculty of Fukien Christian University (FCU).
  - FCU faculty group images, 1927-circa 1933 (Box-folder 3: 9)
- Memorabilia, 1924, undated
  Consists of a postcard, a silk screen painting with a letter to Roderick, posters and other papers.
  - Postcard, undated (Box-folder 3: 10)
  - Identification cards and booklets, undated (Box-folder 3: 11)
  - FCU promotional publication, 1924 (Box-folder 3: 12)
  - Letter and painting from a student to Roderick Scott on a piece of silk, 1924 (Map Case)
  - 2 certificates of achievement, undated (Map Case)
    In Chinese
  - Proclamation, undated (Map Case)